American Song Sheets, 1850-1870 M1628.2.A5
Lilly Library
- 122. Happy Land of Canaan. No.2 - Now kind folks, I'm going to sing a song (5 verses and chorus.) As sung by Toney Pastor. New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan clown, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 123. The Harp. - Magic harp of Erin! what stills thy sweet cadence (5 verses.) By Charles Conroy. N.p., n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.
- 124. The Harp of Old Erin and Banner of Stars. - The war trump has sounded, our rights are in danger (4 verses.) Air - "St. Patrick's Day." Dedicated to Charles J. Murphy, 1st Lieut., Scott Life-Guard, N.Y., by his sincere friend, Thomas Kean. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship. Wolf 854.
- 125. Have You Seen My Sister. A Highly Popular Comic Song. - Say, my lovely friends, have you any pity (6 verses.) Tune. - "Bob and John." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Not in Wolf.
- 126. Heather Dale. - The peaceful little valley (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan clown, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 127. Heenan the Champion of the World. - Who was it crossed the raging ocean (5 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan harp, colored. Wolf 869.
- 128. He Led Her to the Altar. - He led her to the altar (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan fountain, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 129. Her Heart Is the Prize I Will Gain. - To the Ball, to the Ball, I'll pursue her (3 verses.) Composed by F. W. N. Bayley. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments, colored. Wolf 872.
- 130. Hicks the Pirate. - A mournful tale heart rending (5 verses.) Air: "The Rose Tree." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp, colored. See Wolf 881.
- 131. The Hod Carrier's Song. - l am a bold Hodman, I live by my trade (6 verses and chorus.) Air.- "Villikens and His Dinah." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid, colored. Wolf 887a.
- 132. Hoist Up the Flag. - Away down in Dixie, the war first begun (7 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship with war scenes in lower comers. Wolf 888d.
- 133. Hoist Up the Flag Long May It Wave. - The Rebels thought they had us when the war first begun (11 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Auner-Johnson. Wolf 889e.
- 134. Hold Your Horses. - Now hold your horses, will you' and do not drive so fast ( 3 verses and chorus.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 163 la.
- 135. Holy Friar. A Humorous Song. - I am a Friar of orders Gray (2 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: George S. Harris, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.
- 136. Home Again. - Home again, home again (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. See Wolf 891.
- 137. The Home Where Roses Grew. - Oh! how often, when at eve I'm sitting (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan trapper, colored. Wolf 897.
- 138. Hoops, No.2. What a Ridiculous Fashion? - Now Crinoline is all the rage with ladies of whatever age (6 verses and chorus.) Air: "King of the Cannibal Islands." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. Wolf 904b.
- 139. How Sheridan Whipped Longstreet. - It was just before the day break, that this famous fight began (5 verses.) Air - "Jeannette and Jeannot." By John Ross Dix, October 19th, 1864. New York: Charles Magnus, ©1864. Letter paper, blue ink. Headpiece: Magnus 159, colored. Wolf 920g.
- 140. How Sweet Are the Roses. - How sweet, how sweet are the roses (3 verses.) Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.
- 141. How the Gates Came Ajar. - 'Twas whispered one morning in Heaven (4 verses and chorus.) Words by H. L. Bostwick. Music by Eastburn. Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Not in Wolf.
- 142. Hurdy-Gurdy Man. - I am not so very happy, nor am I so very sad (4 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Not in Wolf.
- 143. Hurrah for the Land We Love! - Harrah for the land we love! (2 verses.) Air: "A Life on the Ocean Wave." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border De Marsan eagle, colored. See Wolf 938.
- 144. The Husband's Dream. - Why Dermot you look healthy, now your dress is neat and clean (8 verses.) A Companion to the "Wife's Dream." Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Auner-Johnson. See Wolf 946.
- 145. The Husband's Dream. - Why Dermot you look healthy now, your dress is neat and clean (8 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Wolf 946b.
- 146. I'Am not Myself at All. - Oh! I'm not myself at all, Molly dear, Molly dear (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid, colored. See Wolf 954.
- 147. I'd Be a Gipsy. - I'd be a gipsy merry and free (2 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Wolf 997.
- 148. I'd Choose to Be a Baby. - I'd choose to be a baby (4 verses and chorus.) Original version and Tony Pastor's version. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan's comic heads. See Wolf 998.
- 149. I'd Mourn the Hopes that Leave Me. - I'd mourn the hopes that leave me (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. See Wolf 1000.
- 150. I Dream of Home. - I dream of my home, happy home of my childhood (3 verses and chorus.) Sung by G. C. Glendale, at Bryants' Minstrels, Mechanics' Hall, 472 Broadway. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Wolf 960.
- 151. I Had a Dream. - I had a dream, a happy dream (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan trapper. Wolf 963.
- 152. I Know not if She Loves Me. - I know not if she loves me (2 verses.) Second song: "When We Dwell on the Lips." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. See Wolf 970.
- 153. I'll Hang My Harp on a Willow Tree. - I'll hang my harp on a willow tree (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. See Wolf 1008.
- 154. I'll Never Forget Thee. - "Forget thee?" - If to dream by night (3 verses.) [New York?: Andrews?], n.d. Border: Andrews ivy. See Wolf 1009.
- 155. I'll Never Forget Thee, Dear Mary. - My heart wanders back, o'er the waters (3 verses.) Words by George Cooper. Music by T. B. Bishop. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. Not in Wolf.
- 156. I'll Throw Myself Away. - Now, ladies, your attention! (4 verses and chorus.) N.p., n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 101la.
- 157. I'll Touch My Harp. - Oft in that calm and gentle hour (2 verses.) Sung nightly with Shouts of Applause by W. Vincent. at his new and beautiful opera house, No.49 Bowery. Directly opposite the Bowery Theatre. Second song: "False One, I Love Thee Still." New York: J. Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 1012a.
- 158. I'll Woo Thee in the Summer Time. - I'll woo thee in the summer time (3 verses.) Words by R. Scott Cowenlock. - Music. by Chas. J. Hargitt. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. See Wolf 1013.
- 159. I Loved That Dear Old Flag the Best. - Look within my knapsack (4 verses and chorus.) Words by Ednor Rossiter. Music by B. Frank Walters. Rev. M. P. Gaddis relates...[narrative of a dying soldier]. Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Wolf 974b.
- 160. I Miss Thee So. - I miss thee so in our cottage home (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments, colored. See Wolf 975.
- 161. I'm Lonely Since My Mother Died. - I'm lonely since my mother died (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 1018.
- 162. I'm Off for Nicaragua. - One day, while walking down Broadway (6 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 163. I'm Turning Gray, Dear Kate. - Time's hand is even there, sweet Kate (2 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. See Wolf 1025.
- 164. Independence Day. - Squeak the fife and beat the drum (6 verses.) As sung by Mrs. Barney Williams and Mrs. Florence, throughout the States. Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Auner-Johnson. Wolf 1039c.
- 165. The Indian Warrior's Grave. - Green is the grave by the wild dashing river (3 verses.) Second song: "Indian Hunter." New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1047a.
- 166. Indian Warrior's Grave. - Green is the grave by the wild dashing river (3 verses.) Second song: "No.2. Indian Hunter." Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 1044.
- 167. Innocent Mike. - I am a wandering Irishman, they call me Innocent Mike (5 verses.) Air - "Low Backed Car." Words by G. W. Anderson. New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1049a.
- 168. In the Days When We Went Gipsying. - In the days when we went gipsying (3 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 1036.
- 169. I Promised I Would Never Leave Her. - Now, look on this warrior bold (6 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Wolf 977
- 170. The Irish Brigade. - When brave hearts shall be a reproach to a nation (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid, colored. Wolf 1053.
- 171. The Irishman. - The savage loves his native shore (5 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. Not in Wolf.
- 172. Irishman's Shanty. - Did ye 's ever go intil an Irishman's shanty? (8 verses.) Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.
- 173. The Irish Refugee, or Poor Pat Must Emigrate. - Fare you well, poor Erin's Isle! (6 verses.) Air - "Podgee and Rhu." Sung by J. S. Berry. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Wolf 1060.
- 174. The Irish Stranger. - Oh, pity, the fate of a poor Irish stranger (6 verses.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.
- 175. The Irish Wide-Awake. - As I walked out one evening (4 verses and chorus.) Air: "Billy O. Rourke." - By Harry M. Palmer. New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan trapper, colored. Wolf 1067.
- 176. Isle of Beauty, Fare Thee Well. - Shades of ev'ning close not o'er us (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 177. Isn't It a Wonder? - Sister Norf and Sister Souff(4 verses.) Written by Henry Wood, Esq. and sung by Wood's Minstrels, with most enthusiastic applause. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. See Wolf 1071a.
- 178. Is that Mother Bending O'er Me? - Is that mother? Is that mother bending o'er me (2 verses and chorus.) No.821. Boston: Horace Partridge, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1069b.
- 179. I Stood Amid the Glittering Throng. - I stood amid the glittering throng (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. See Wolf 982.
- 180. I Think of Old Ireland Wherever I Go. - I'm a wanderer, now, from the land of my birth (8 verses and chorus.) Air - "My Heart's in the Highlands." Written by J. H. Howard. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 181. It's Wonderful How We Do It, but We Do. - Napoleon used to say: There's no such word as Fail (5 verses.) Sung by Tony Pastor at his Opera-House, 201 Bowery. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Wolf 1077
- 182. I've Wandered by the Hut Side. - I've wandered by the hut side (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. Wolf 1078b.
- 183. I Vish I Vas de Mayor. - Last night I vent me oud, und I dolt you all aboud (2 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Wavy line above and below verses. Not in Wolf.
- 184. The Ivy Green. - Oh! a dainty plant is the ivy green (3 verses.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1079.
- 185. Jack Muggins, or The Donkey-Balancer. - Of all the strange tales about asses (9 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. See Wolf 1081.
- 186. Jamie's on the Stormy Sea. - E'eer the twilight bat was fletting (4 verses.) As sung by John Hassett. A four-line verse, "Constancy," follows the song. New York: H. Marsan, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.
- 187. Jamie's on the Stormy Sea. - E'eer the twilight bat was fletting (4 verses.) As sung by John Hassett. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 188. Jenny Lane. - When I was young and in my prime (2 verses and chorus.) Sung by Wm. A. Wray, the Celebrated Banjoist with great applause. New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Andrews ivy. See Wolf 1106.
- 189. Jersey Calves. - I am a jolly roving blade, and in Jersey I was bred (6 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. Wolf 1112.
- 190. The Jersey Lovers. - Of a heart-rending tragidy (6 verses.) A Pathetic Ballad. As sung by Bryant's, Wood's and Campbell's Minstrels. Words and Music by Eugene T. Johnson.... No. 1264. New York: J. Wrigley, n.d. Border: Wrigley Ethiopian. See Wolf 1114.
- 191. Jimmy Riddle. - Now, I'll tell you, if I can, of a pretty girl named Nan (5 verses and chorus.) As sung by Harry Richmond. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 1119.
- 192. The Jockey Hat and Feather. - As I was walking out, one day (3 verses and chorus.) Sung by W. N. Smith, the great bone-player, of Bailey's Circus. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan trapper. Wolf 1 120a.
- 193. Joe Hardy. - Yes, I know that you once were my lover (6 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. Wolf 1 123a.
- 194. John Bull. - John Bull don't you remember (6 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 195. Johnny Doyle! - l am a fair maiden, all tangled in love (11 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. See Wolf 1 138a (with De Marsan comic heads border).
- 196. Johnny, Fill Up the Bowl. - Abram Lincoln, what yer 'bout? (4 verses.) Free-and-Easy Song. By Saul Sertrew. Boston: Horace Partridge, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 1139.
- 197. Johnny Is Gone for a Soldier. - I'll trace these gardens o'er and o'er (5 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship with war scenes in lower comers. See Wolf 1143.
- 198. Johnny's So Bashful! - They tell me the roses are leaving my cheek (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. Wolf 1147a.
- 199. The Jolly Old Crow. - On the limb of an oak sat a jolly old crow (3 verses and chorus.) Sung nightly with shouts of applause, by Charley White at his Opera House, 49 Bowery, N.Y. New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1150.
- 200. Jolly Spree. - My song relates about the time (8 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments, colored. Wolf 1153a.
- 201. The Jolly Young Waterman. - And did you ne 'er hear of a jolly young waterman (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, © 1860. Border: De Marsan trapper, colored. See Wolf 1154.
- 202. Jordan Is a Hard Road to Travel. No.4. - Of all the banjo songs that have been sung of late (7 verses and chorus.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1157a.
- 203. Juliana, Phebiana, Constantina Brown. - Oh! I'm going to sing a song to you Juliana Brown (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan trapper. Not in Wolf.
- 204. The Lads Who Live in Ireland, or Where Apple Praties Grow. - My name is Ned O'Manney, I was born in sweet Killarney (7 verses.) Composed and Sung by Jas. Seymour, at Niblo's, in the "Duke's Motto." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship with war scenes in lower comers. Wolf 1206.
- 205. Lamentation for J. P. Donnelly. - All you, who 're tender hearted, come and listen to my song (7 verses.) Words by H. J. Howard. - Gaelic air. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan homed imp, colored. Wolf 1211.
- 206. Lament of the Irish Emigrant. - I'm sitting on the stile, Mary (6 verses.) No.433. New York: J. Wrigley, n.d. Border: Wrigley homed imp. Not in Wolf.
- 207. The Land of Shillelah! - I was just on my way starting home from Sligo (5 verses.) Sung by Wm. H. Lindsey. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan trapper. Not in Wolf.
- 208. Larboard Watch. Duett. - At dreary midnight's cheerless hour (2 verses and chorus.) Second song: "The Gondolier." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Not in Wolf.
- 209. Larry O'Gaff. - Near a bog in sweet Ire land. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. See Wolf 2220.
- 210. The Lass of Gowrie. - 'Twas on a simmer's afternoon (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Wolf 1221.
- 211. The Last Link Is Broken. - The last link is broken that bound me to thee (3 verses and chorus.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1224a.
- 212. The Last Potato. - 'Tis my last, last potato! (3 verses.) Parody on: "'Tis the Last Rose of Summer." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Wolf 1226a.
- 213. Laughing Song. - My story, yes, c'est amoureuse (3 verses.) From Auber's "Manon Lescaut." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Wolf 1230.
- 214. Lazy Club. - My wife is such a lazy Turk (7 verses and chorus.) Air - "Green Grow the Rushes, Oh!". New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Wolf 1232a.
- 215. Liberty Tree. - In a chariot of light, from the regions of day (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan eagle, colored. See Wolf 1248.
- 216. Life Let Us Cherish. - Life let us cherish, while yet the taper glows (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 217. A Life on the Ocean Wave. - A life on the ocean wave! (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. See Wolf 1250.
- 218. Linda Has Departed. - Death with his cold hand, hath robb'd me of evry hope (2 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. See Wolf 1265.
- 219. Linger Not, Darling. Serenade. - Linger not, darling, awake from they sleep (2 verses and chorus.) Words by George Cooper. Music by J. R. Thomas. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Wolf 1275a.
- 220. Little Alice. - Oh! I knew you little Alice (3 verses and chorus.) Words by George Cooper. Music by Henry Hyatt. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 1278
- 221. Little Bare-Foot. - Standing where the bleak winds whistled (3 verses and chorus.) Words and Music by Frank Howard. Sung by Miss Maggie Mitchell in the popular Drama of that name. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. Wolf 1279.
- 222. The Little Blacksmith. - We heard his hammer all day long (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan clown, colored. See Wolf 1280.
- 223. Little Eva. To Her Papa. - When your daughter's ta'en away, and your heart is filled with care (3 verses.) As sung by Little Cordelia Howard, in the successful Drama of "Uncle Tom's Cabin," at the National Theatre, N.Y. Second song: "Little Eva in Heaven." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. See Wolf 1283.
- 224. Little Major. - At his post the little major (4 verses and chorus.) No.968. N.p., n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1288.
- 225. Little Nell. The Heroine of "The Old Curiosity Shop." - They told him gently she was dead (3 verses and chorus.) Words by Casserly. - Music by T. Bissell. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Wolf 1290.
- 226. Little Sally's Wooden Ware. - Come, buy poor Sall'ys wooden ware (2 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 227. Little Topsy's Song. - Topsy neber was born, neber had a moder (3 verses and 3 choruses.) Words by Eliza Cook - Music by Hutchinson. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp, colored. Wolf 1294b.
- 228. Lora Vale. - Calmly fell the silver Moon-light (3 verses and 3 choruses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Not in Wolf.
- 229. Lottie in the Lane. - The Sun was going down to rest (3 verses and chorus.) As sung by Bryants' Minstrels. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. Wolf 1314a.
- 230. Lovely Dolly Day. - I've told you 'bout de banjo (4 verses and chorus.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Andrews ivy. Wolf 1320.
- 231. Lovely Mary. - I'll taste no more of the poison'd cup (4 verses.) Air - "Highland Mary". New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. See Wolf 1322.
- 232. Mc'Donald's Return to Glenco. - As I went a walking one evening of late (11 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. See Wolf 1354.
- 233. Major Andre's Arrest and Execution. - Come all you gallant heroes, I pray you, lend an ear (11 verses.) Air - "Dog and Gun". New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan Yankee pedlar, colored. Wolf 1363.
- 234. Man the Life Boat. - Man the life boat! man the life boat (4 verses.) By Henry Russall. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. See Wolf 1268.
- 235. The Man Who Lost His Breeches. - On a night both dark and thick, while asleep in the forecastle (6 verses.) Air - "Courting in the Kitchen". New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.
- 236. Maria, the Dustman's Wife. - Oh! once, there lived, in Bowling-Green (6 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Wolf 1382.
- 237. Mariner's Grave. - I remember the night was stormy and wet (6 verses.) Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Auner-Johnson. See Wolf 1383.
- 238. Marseilles Hymn. - Ye sons of freedom, wake to glory! (4 verses and chorus.) Revised and Printed expressly for the Public Schools. N.p., n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 1385.
- 239. The Marseilles Hymn. - Ye sons of Freedom, wake to glory! (4 verses and chorus.) No. 152. Boston: Horace Partridge, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 1385.
- 240. Mary Blane. - Oh! once I loved a yellow gal (4 verses and chorus.) Headline: "New Song." [New York]: Andrews, n.d. Border: Andrews ivy. See Wolf 1389a.
- 241. Maud Adair and I. - One year ago were we sixteen (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan trapper, colored. Not in Wolf.
- 242. Meeting of the Waters. - There is not in the wide world a valley so sweet (4 verses.) Second song: "Remember Thee!". New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. See Wolf 1415.
- 243. Meet Me by Moonlight Alone. - Meet me by moonlight alone (2 verses.) Second song: "How Dear to Me the Hour!" New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Wolf 141 lb.
- 244. Minnie Dear. - Minnie dear has left us (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. Wolf 1437a.
- 245. Misfortunes of Barney O'Neil. - Oh, listen now, Ladies and Gentlemen (4 verses and chorus.) Air - "Broth of a Boy". New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Wolf 1442a.
- 246. Mississippi Boat Song. - Some boats are fast and others slow (3 verses and chorus.) Sung by Jerry Bryant, at Bryant's Minstrels, 472 Broadway, N.Y. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. See Wolf 1446.
- 247. Mister Finagan. - I'm a dacent laboring youth (8 verses and chorus.) No.652. N.p., n.d. Border: Moon. See Wolf 1483.